Kaylee Swenson

MU Profile • Website • kscf5@umsystem.edu • (316) 253-5339

Summary

Political science Ph.D. candidate studying NASA and the American space industry, public opinion, American bureaucracy, and qualitative methods. Experienced in analyzing, summarizing, and presenting complex information to a wide audience, in addition to data management. Leadership roles have lead to exemplary communication skills and significant experience in planning and executing social and educational events.

Education

PhD, Political Science, University of Missouri

Expected May 2024

 Relevant coursework includes methodology related to data management, discussion sections relating to government entities and actions, and professionalization courses.

MA, American Studies, Northeastern State University, Oklahoma

August 2018

 Relevant coursework included a course on American political behavior, as well as two sections of constitutional law. During this degree I also completed the Introductory Leadership Certificate through Northeastern State University.

BA, magna cum laude, Visual Communication, Northeastern State University, Oklahoma

May 2016

 Included coursework centering around verbal, written, and visual forms of communication. Common assignments included writing articles for newspapers, developing ads and websites for local businesses, and presenting speeches.

Work Experience

University of Missouri

Columbia, Missouri

Supervisor: Dr. James Endersby (endersby@missouri.edu, 573-882-4238)

o Teaching Assistant/Graduate Instructor (20 hours per week)

Fall 2019 - Present

Assistant to the professor for undergraduate-level courses, handling communication with students, grading, and administrative tasks such as fielding exams. For one semester served as the instructor of record.

o Research Assistant (10 hours per week)

Summer 2022

Assistant to professors regarding their research, with tasks including data collection and management, summarizing previous research, and book indexing.

Summer 2020 Summer 2019

o Archival Research (Single day)

September 2020

Locating/replicating original documents found in the archives of the State Historical Society of Missouri for Dr. Rod Kiewiet (CalTech)

Zoe Institute

Tahlequah, Oklahoma

Supervisor: Ed Blanchard (edb@zoeinstitute.com, 918-557-3162)

o Day Center Intern (20 hours per week)

Summer 2018

Intern at the Day Center, a center for community members experiencing homelessness to receive aid and services. Intern tasks were primarily data management, in addition to assisting with meals and cleaning.

Northeastern State University

Tahlequah, Oklahoma

Supervisor: Whitney Arbaugh (rolph@nsuok.edu, 918-864-0450)

responsibilities for an entire residence hall building.

University Housing Resident Assistant/Student Hall Director (20 hours per week)
Responded to emergencies, handled administrative tasks, and planned community programs for the residence halls. Initially responsible for a single floor of residents as a Resident Assistant, then as Student Hall Director led a team of Resident Assistants with

Fall 2014-Summer 2018

Service

Coordinating Assistant, APSA Peer-to-Peer Pedagogical Conference, Columbia, MO	August 2022
President, Graduate Association of Political Scientists, University of Missouri	2021-2022
Secretary, Graduate Association of Political Scientists, University of Missouri	2020-2021

Invited Talks

"Space Warfare," an introduction to the modern space arms race, presented to Political	Spring 2023
Science 4412: Strategy and Warfare. <i>University of Missouri</i>	
"Chinese Space Policy," an introduction to China's space industry, presented to	Spring 2023
Political Science 4680: Chinese Politics and Foreign Policy, University of Missouri	

Awards & Certificates

o Graduate Assistantship, Truman School of Government and Public Affairs	2019-Present
o Gus T. Ridgel Fellowship, <i>University of Missouri</i>	2019-Present
o Public Engagement Certificate, University of Missouri	Ongoing
o Online Teaching Certification, <i>University of Missouri</i>	Spring 2023
o Introductory Leadership Certificate, Northeastern State University	Spring 2017

References

Feel free to contact any supervisors listed in Work Experience. Below you will find contact information for some of my committee members at the University of Missouri, who can speak to the skills developed during my time in this Ph.D. program.

Name	Employer	Title	Email
Dr. James Endersby	University of Missouri	Professor	Endersby@missouri.edu
Dr. Lael Keiser	University of Missouri	Director of Truman School of Government and Public Affairs	Keiserl@missouri.edu
Dr. Linda Godwin	University of Missouri	Professor Emeritus	Godwinl@missouri.edu